Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Nine
Attack and Defense
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Akira Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Kai
Hi
ni
ra
ku
Koro
gu
no
shi
Na
Kai
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
（ブレーキ音）
（入江(いりえ)）ん？
富竹(とみたけ)さん!?
Tomitake-san!?
If you get even the slightest of bad hunches...
（赤坂(あかさか)）
少しでもイヤな予感がしたら
緊急時と判断していいでしょう
...you should treat it as an emergency.
敵は 私たちを
生かしてはおきません
The enemy isn't going to let us live.
（隊員）入江所長が
女王感染者宅に電話してます！
Director Irie is calling the Queen Carrier's house!
Is he trying to let someone know Tomitake has been caught?
（鷹野(たかの)）富竹が捕まったことを
知らせようというのかしら？
ンッフフフ…
I've grabbed you by your tail.
しっぽを捕まえたわよ
（隊員）ん？　三佐
Major!
裏口のモニターカメラに
入江所長の姿が…
We can see Director Irie through the surveillance camera at the back entrance!
Seize him!
（鷹野）捕らえなさい！　早く！
Hurry!
Phoenix One to security vehicle.
（小此木(おこのぎ)）
鳳(おおとり)１より保安車両　現在位置は？
What's his current location?
（隊員）５丁目付近 林道
最悪の場合 街のほうに抜けます
A forest road in the vicinity of district five.
In a worst case scenario, he will flee to the city.
Don't let him reach the city.
（小此木）街には行かすな
（隊員）了解　砲撃します
Roger.
We're going to fire.
If I let it ring for one minute and hang up, it means it's dangerous there.
１分間鳴らして切れば
“そこは危険　脱出せよ”
Escape immediately.
それ以上 鳴らし続ければ
“連絡不能”
If I let it ring any longer, it means I am unable to contact you.
Head to the Sonozaki estate immediately.
“ただちに園崎(そのざき)家へ急行せよ”
Ten more seconds.
（赤坂）
あと10秒 ９ ８ ７ ６…
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
三佐！　女王感染者宅の
監視班からです
Major!
Message from our surveillance squad at the Queen Carrier's house!
不審な男が
飛び出してきたとのことです
A suspicious man just fled the house.
A man?
男？
Seize him!
捕らえて！
（赤坂）入江の電話は
１分以上 鳴り続けた
Irie left the phone ringing for over a minute.
メッセージの真意は分からないが
緊急度は決して低くない
While I don't know the real meaning of the message...
...the degree of urgency is undoubtedly high.
このまま ぶっちぎって
園崎家に急ぐか…
Should I keep running now, straight to the Sonozaki estate?
それとも…
Or perhaps...
（入江）
今 捕まるわけにはいかない
今は まだ…
I can't let myself get caught now!
Not yet...!
（詩音(しおん)の鼻歌）
Shion-san.
（葛西(かさい)）詩音さん ご機嫌ですね
（詩音）ん？
You're in a good mood.
だって
１年に１度の綿流しのお祭りですよ
It's the yearly Watanagashi festival, after all!
お姉たちをどうおちょくろうか
楽しみじゃないですか
How shall I fool Sis and the others?
I'm looking forward to that!
はあ そうですか　ん？
Is that so...
（詩音）監督？
（入江）う…
Manager?
Don't tell me that's your car, Manager?
まさか あれ 監督の車ですか？
（入江）し… 詩音さん
Sh-Shion-san...
Are you okay?
（葛西）
大丈夫ですか？　すぐに病院に…
Let's get you to the hospital right away.
し… 診療所は困ります
T-The clinic isn't an option.
園崎家に行かないと…　うっ
I have to go to...
...the Sonozaki estate...
Manager!
監督!?
詩音さん　わけありのようです
Shion-san.
This doesn't seem to have been an accident.
入江先生の車に弾痕が
There is a bullet hole in Dr. Irie's car.
Seriously?
（詩音）マジ？
Let's take him to the main house for now.
ひとまず本家に連れていこう
Huh?
（詩音）あれ？　どこ行くの？
Where are you going?
敵はタイヤを狙ってました
生かして捕らえるつもりです
The enemy was aiming for the tires.
They intended to capture him alive.
私たちのすぐ近くに
追っ手がいたかもしれません
There might have been pursuers right behind us.
でも この地形じゃ
密着尾行以外は不可能でしょう
But in this terrain, it'd be impossible for them to follow us unless they tailed us closely.
Just to be safe.
念のためです
もう何回か方向を変えたら
本家へ向かいます
I will head for the main house after changing directions a few more times.
詩音さんは
後方監視をお願いします
Shion-san, please watch our rear.
了解
Roger.
（隊員）保安より本部
Security to HQ.
標的は民間車に拾われた模様
車両情報を送る
It seems the target has been picked up by a civilian vehicle.
We will send you information on the vehicle.
（隊員）本部 了解
HQ, roger.
Warbler in pursuit: change your target to the civilian vehicle.
追跡中の鶯(うぐいす)は民間車両に標的を変更
至急 捜索せよ
Locate it immediately.
入江所長は 極力 生きたままで捕獲
接触民間人も制圧せよ　ただし―
Make every effort to capture Director Irie alive.
Seize the civilians as well.
But you may capture them dead or alive!
生死は問わない！
Is it going okay?
大丈夫なの？　すぐに見つかるの!?
Will you find him soon?
Rest assured.
ご安心を
所長の白衣には発信機が
There is a transmitter hidden in the Director's lab coat.
Warbler Three.
（隊員）鶯３　標的車両を発見
水車小屋前を小道に入った
Target vehicle located.
They entered a path right before the water mill.
（隊員）もう ここは私有地です
Everything from here on is private land.
At the end of this road...
その先は…
（鷹野）ンッフフフ…
Sonozaki Estate
My, my.
あらあら　袋のネズミねえ
Cornered like rats.
[Sonozaki]
Mii-chan!
（レナ）
魅(み)ぃちゃん　車が入ってきたよ
A car arrived.
（魅音(みおん)）これは葛西さんの車だね
This is Kasai-san's car.
It's probably Shion.
たぶん詩音でしょう
今日の祭りに合わせて
遊びに来たってとこだろうね
She likely came to hang out for the festival today.
She really can't read an atmosphere.
ったく空気読めない奴
（レナ）あれ？
（魅音）ん？
Huh?
Manager!?
監督!?
Manager!
（魅音）監督ー！
んっ…　すみません
富竹さんが山狗(やまいぬ)に捕まりました
Sorry.
Tomitake-san has been caught by the Yamainu.
They chased after me when I ran away, and I ended up having an accident.
私は逃げる時に
奴らに追われて事故を…
What about pursuers?
追っ手は？
There was no one on our tail.
尾行はなかった
（車の走行音）
つけられてんじゃん！
詩音のバカ！
You were being followed after all!
Stupid Shion!
つけられてないもん　お姉のバカ！
We weren't being followed!
Stupid Sis!
Anyway, let's go inside.
とにかく中へ
This is Phoenix One.
（小此木）こちら鳳１　標的を発見
Target located.
その友人 数人も確認
As well as several of his friends.
ンッフフフ…　間違いないわ
梨花(りか)は そこに潜んでるのよ
There's no doubt about it.
Rika is hiding over there.
そうよね？　ジロウさん
Isn't that right...
...Jirou-san?
Oh, right...
（鷹野）あらあら…
お返事できないんだったわね
...you were unable to answer.
（隊員）いたぞ！
There they are!
（一同）どわああ
Be careful!
（隊員）注意しろ！
辺りはトラップだらけだ！
This place is filled with traps!
（レナ）大丈夫かな？
Will it hold?
簡単に破られないでしょうが
荒事に慣れている連中のようです
I don't think it can be broken down easily...
...but they seem to be professionals.
過信しないほうがいいでしょう
We shouldn't place too much trust in it.
（圭一(けいいち)）とにかく奥へ
Anyway, let's head further in!
ああ はいはい
わたしゃ事情が分からないまま―
Yes, okay, okay!
I'm about to reach the climax without ever knowing the situation!
いきなりクライマックスですよ
はーい
Okay!
（魅音）ああ もう！
（詩音）ぶー
Oh, geez!
（魅音）あんたにも ５分
時間できたら 全部 説明するから！
If you gave me five minutes, I could explain everything to you!
（隊員）鶯１より鳳１　標的は
防空壕(ごう)のような所に逃げ込んだ
Warbler One to Phoenix One.
The target fled into a place that looks like a bomb shelter.
The door is made of steel, so we can't infiltrate.
扉は鋼鉄製　突破できない
（小此木）鳳１ 了解
Phoenix One, roger.
These Sonozaki people are extremely rich.
この園崎家って奴は
とんでもない金持ちだなあ
敷地が広すぎて包囲は不可能だ
We can't surround the place because the land is too big.
Phoenix Seven to Phoenix One.
（隊員）鳳７より鳳１
インドア用のプラ爆があります
We have some indoor-use plastic explosives.
Shall we install them?
準備しますか？
さすがに真っ昼間に爆破は無理だな
Using explosives in broad daylight is probably impossible.
いや 待てよ　今 何時だ？
（隊員）もうじき10時です
No, wait...
What time is it?
Almost ten.
How convenient.
使えるぞ
Phoenix Seven.
鳳７　信管を準備しろ
Prepare for detonation.
Is everyone okay?
（梨花）みんな 大丈夫ですか？
（羽入(はにゅう)）あうあう～
これで見た感じでは
敵は30人くらい いますです
As far as we can tell, there are about thirty enemies outside.
（圭一）そんなにかよ!?
やってくれるぜ
That many!?
They're serious.
（魅音）ちょっと替えるよ
Gonna change it for a bit...
アッハハハ
連中 立ち往生してるよ
They're at a standstill.
（詩音）お姉
Sis?
事情はどうあれ この状況なら―
Whatever the circumstances are...
...doesn't this situation more than justify a call to the police?
もう十分 警察に
電話できる段階じゃありません？
だねえ　一番最初の
市民の権利を忘れてたよ
Doesn't it?
I'd forgotten about our very first civil right.
What's wrong, Mion?
Doesn't even make a beep.
うんともすんとも言わない
おそらく すべてのケーブルが
切断されたのでしょう
They probably cut all of the cables.
They struck the weak point of an underground hideout.
地下の弱点を突かれたね
だけど あの扉は
爆弾でも使わない限り―
Even so...
...as long as they don't use any explosives on that door...
そう簡単には破れないよ
...we won't be beaten that easily.
それに こんな真っ昼間に
爆発音なんかしたら―
Besides...
...if they make an explosion in broad daylight...
それこそ警察が来るに違いないよ
...that will no doubt call out the police for us.
（沙都子(さとこ)）はっ　監督は
綿流しの本部役員ですわよね？
Manager, you were in the organization committee for the Watanagashi festival, right?
When will the decision be made whether or not to cancel the festival due to rain?
今日のお祭り 雨天決行の判断は？
If I remember correctly, at 10 a.m. with fireworks...
確か 午前10時に花火で…
ああっ！
（羽入）あうあう！
まさか その音に混じって…
Are they going to mingle with that sound to...!?
（隊員）もうじき10時です
It's almost ten.
Do it.
（小此木）やれ
（魅音）さあ 入って　この奥だよ
Go in.
It's beyond here.
（圭一）こいつを下りろってのか
Do we have to descend this?
You'll come across a tunnel on the way down.
（魅音）
下りてくと 途中に横穴があるの
そこを抜ければ 山中の古井戸に
抜けられるようになってる
If you follow that tunnel, you can reach an old well in the mountains.
ってことは―
Meaning...
...you are the most familiar with the path, so you will lead.
一番 詳しいお姉がトップです
（魅音）え？
Who else is here to do it?
他に誰がいるんです？
しんがりは私と葛西が務めます
Me and Kasai will guard the rear.
ちょ…　それ どういうことか
分かってんの!?
Wh...
Do you know what you're getting yourself into!?
分かってるよ！
I do!
分かった
Okay.
Mion-san.
魅音さん　武器庫の鍵を
The key to the armory.
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
いいよ！
梨花ちゃんから下りてきて
Okay!
Rika-chan, you come down first!
Rika!
（羽入）梨花！
（一同）ああ…
（梨花）大丈夫
I'm fine.
（梨花）クソッ…
私は昭和58年６月を越える
Damn it...
I will live past June 1983.
And then I'm going to grow much taller.
そしてね もっともっと
身長が伸びるのよ
My breasts are going to get bigger.
胸だって もっと大きくなる
いつまでも こんな子供の体なんて
絶対にゴメンなんだから
I'm not going to stay in a child's body for the rest of my life!
Warbler Seven to Phoenix One.
（隊員）鶯７より鳳１
ワイヤー感応のトラップを発見
Wire traps detected.
突入は慎重を要す
We have to infiltrate with caution.
Phoenix, roger.
鳳 了解
There are many traces of traps.
トラップの痕跡 少なくありません
通電を検討されては…
Should we turn the electricity back on?
バカ野郎！
Moron.
そんなことしたら連中が
逃げやすくなっちまうじゃねえか
That's going to make it really easy for them to escape!
これほどのデカい壕(ほり)だ
別に出口がきっとある
It's a massive shelter.
There's bound to be a different exit somewhere.
They're going to try and escape from there.
必ず そこから
逃げようとするはずだ　急がせろ！
Tell them to get a move on!
Stay calm so you don't fall.
（詩音）焦って落ちないようにね
（圭一）ん…　あ…
その井戸 歴代
園崎家に逆らった連中の死体を―
Rumor has it...
...that over the generations, this bottomless well was used as a dump for corpses of those who opposed the Sonozaki family.
捨てるのに使ったってうわさもある
底なしの井戸ですから
し… 詩音！
やっぱり その役は俺がやる
S-Shion!
I think it's best if I do your part after all.
次は詩音が下りろ
You should go down next.
圭ちゃんの男のプライド
サンキューです
Thanks for your male pride.
でも圭ちゃんに
カラシニコフの説明をするより―
But we're going to lose a lot of time if I have to explain to you how to use a Kalashnikov first.
キリキリ下りてくれるほうが
ロスタイムは少ないです
でも…
But...
気にしないで
いい女は死なないから
Don't worry.
Good women don't die.
それにね…
Besides...
拷問室まで来ました
（詩音）早く！
They made it to the torture chamber.
Hurry!
Shion!
詩音…
Tell this to Sis.
（詩音）お姉に伝えて
（圭一）あ…
"It'd be nice if we could be twins again in the next life."
私たち 来世も双子がいいねって
（魅音）詩音のバカー！
早く下りてー！
Stupid Shion!
Hurry up and come down!
イヤよ　誰が欠けてもイヤ！
No...
I don't want to give up anyone!
梨花…
Rika...
これが最後の世界なのよ
This is the final world!
私はイヤよ
I don't want this!
詩音が死んだり 葛西が
死んだりする未来はゴメンよ！
I don't want a future in which Shion or Kasai die!
イヤよ　イヤ イヤ！
No!
Never!
絶対イヤ！
（爆発音）
Absolutely never!
Hurry up and come down!
早く下りてきてー！
（隊員）クリア
鶯より鳳１　銃眼を制圧
Clear.
Warbler to Phoenix One.
Embrasures neutralized.
（一同）ああ…
（隊員）了解　試みる
Roger.
I'll give it a shot.
（隊員）聞こえるか！
返事をしないでもいい　聞け！
Can you hear me!?
No need to answer!
Listen up!
女王感染者 古手(ふるで)梨花と
診療所所長 入江京介(きょうすけ)を引き渡せ！
Hand over the Queen Carrier, Rika Furude, and the director of the clinic, Kyousuke Irie!
人殺し！　よくも詩音を！
You murderers!
How dare you kill Shion!
Don't worry!
（隊員）安心しろ！
少女も男も生きている！
The girl and the man are alive!
気絶しているだけだ！
They are merely unconscious!
（一同）ああ…
（圭一）生きてる？
They're alive...
Shion!
（魅音）詩音！
I-It's a bluff!
（圭一）ハ… ハッタリだ
落とすわけねえ
They're not going to drop her!
（隊員）
考える時間が必要なら与える！
We will give you some time to think!
ただし 60秒経過したら
最初の人質を突き落とす！
However, after sixty seconds, we will drop the first hostage!
ど… どうしよう…　どうしよう！
W-What do we do...?
What do we do!?
敵の狙いは私です
The enemy is after me.
梨花さんは すでに
脱出してしまったことにして―
We'll tell them Rika-san has already escaped...
私だけが行きます
（レナ）ダメ！
...and I'll go by myself.
No!
詩ぃちゃんたちが 私たちを
逃がす時間を稼いでくれたんだもん
Shii-chan and Kasai-san bought us time to escape!
監督が行ったら―
If you go, then what did they fight so hard for!?
何のために詩ぃちゃんたちが
頑張ってくれたか―
分からなくなっちゃう！
Then what!?
じゃあ 何!?
詩音に死ねって言うの!?
Are you saying Shion should die!?
Please stop it, Mion-san!
やめてくださいまし 魅音さん
私(わたくし)だって
胸が張り裂けそうなんですのよ
My heart is about to burst as well.
だって詩音さんは
私の ねーねーなのに…
After all...
...Shion-san is my Nee-nee...
Shion!
詩音ー！
（梨花）どうすればいいの？
What should we do...?
Hey, Hanyuu!
ねえ 羽入！　どうすればいいの!?
（魅音の泣き声）
What should we do!?
ん…　ボクも分かりませんです
I don't know, either.
Aren't you a god!?
あんた神様でしょう？
何とかしてよ！
Do something!
Use your superpowers, or make some kind of miracle happen!
神通力でも奇跡でも起こしてよ！
梨花　聞きなさい
（梨花）あ…
Rika.
Listen to me!
ボクたちは
共に数多くの世界を渡り―
We have crossed many different worlds together...
人の身では知り得ないことを
いくつも知ってきました
...and learned many things no normal person could ever know.
そして ようやくこの世界で
最も大切なことを学び取りました
And finally, in this world, we learned the most important thing of them all.
それは 奇跡の起こし方
The way to make a miracle happen.
そうね　奇跡の起こし方
You're right...
The way to make a miracle happen.
ん…　また忘れるところだったわ
I almost forgot it again.
Please run away, everyone.
みんなは逃げてください
（梨花）
出ていくのは ボクだけで十分です
It should be plenty if only I go.
There has to be a specific way in which Takano wants to kill me.
ボクの殺し方には 鷹野なりの
こだわりがあるはずなのです
So I probably won't be killed for a while.
だから たぶん
しばらく殺されないのです
R-Rika-chan...
（圭一）り… 梨花ちゃん
大丈夫なのです
ボクたちは絶対に勝てるって―
It's okay.
We can absolutely win this.
I, everyone else, and even god believes it.
ボクも みんなも… そして
神様までも信じているのだから
This isn't even a pinch.
こんなの
ピンチでも何でもないのですよ
にぱ～
ボクの仲間に指一本 触れてみろ
舌をかんで死んでやりますです
Just you try and lay a finger on my friends!
I'll bite through my tongue and die!
鷹野は 自分の手で
ボクを殺したがってますから―
Takano wants to kill me with her own hands.
お前たちは
困ったことになりますですよ？
It would get you guys in a lot of trouble.
I am telling you to comply with my deal!
この私が取引に応じると言っている
Quit whimpering and do as I say!
グズグズせずに言うとおりにせよ！
Peons!
下郎！
じょ… 条件を飲もう
古手梨花は上がれ！
W-We'll accept your conditions!
Rika Furude can come up!
では行ってきますですよ
I'm off, then.
にぱ～
（一同）あ…
（羽入）梨花…
Rika...
（小此木）捜しましたよ　梨花さん
I've been looking for you...
...Rika-san.
あなたは大事な身なんですから―
Your life is quite precious to us.
急に姿を消されちゃ
たまりませんねえ
We can't have you suddenly disappear.
では梨花さんは
診療所に来てもらいましょうか
Then will you come to the clinic with us, Rika-san?
行け
Go.
Are you going to break our agreement!?
約束を破る気!?
Agreement?
約束？　そりゃあ何の話ですんね？
What are you talking about, I wonder?
If you really want to bite your tongue, go right ahead.
本当に舌でも かまれちゃ
かないませんからねえ　おい
Do it.
（梨花）信じてる
I believe.
目を開いて 最初に目にするのは
私の いとしい仲間たちなんだ
That the first thing I will see when I open my eyes...
...are the faces of my beloved friends.
（殴る音）
（隊員）うおああ！
You...
（小此木）お前…　何者だ!?
Who are you!?
I made it.
（赤坂）間に合った
Rika-chan.
梨花ちゃん　君を助けに来た！
I've come to save you!
赤坂！
Akasaka!
行け！
Go!
（赤坂）梨花ちゃん　伏せていて！
（梨花）はいです！
Rika-chan!
Take cover!
Okay!
（隊員）おらあ！
（小此木）ぬあ！　な!?
フウ…
（小此木）んん…
ふああーっ！
Weak.
（赤坂）軽いな
（小此木）あ!?
本当の拳を教えてやる
Let me show you a real punch.
（赤坂）いいーやっ！
（小此木）ああ…　ふんっ　あ…
（エンジン音）
（梨花）みんな…
Everyone!
梨花　無事でよかったのです
Rika!
I'm so glad you're okay!
気絶したフリをして 葛西さんが
反撃のチャンスを作ってくれたんだ
By pretending to be unconscious...
...Kasai-san created a chance for us to strike back.
奇跡のおかげね
Thanks to the miracle.
（羽入）奇跡じゃありませんです
みんなで力を合わせたから
It wasn't a miracle!
It was because we all combined our strength!
You're right...
そうね　この程度で奇跡じゃ
もったいないわね
A miracle would be wasted on something this minor.
さあ！　今度は
こっちが打って出る番なのです
Okay, this time it's our turn to strike!
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Shion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Miyo Takano
Jirou Tomitake
Kyousuke Irie
Mamoru Akasaka
Okonogi
Tatsuyoshi Kasai
Miki Itou
Tohru Ookawa
Toshihiko Seki
Daisuke Ono
Jurota Kosugi
Fumihiko Tachiki
Cast
Yamainu
Satoshi Tsuruoka
Tsutomu Densaka
Nobuyuki Kobushi
Katsuhiro Oota
Toshinobu Iida
Gen Nakano
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hone no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white tip of the bone...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Masashi Suzuki
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Tatsuya Abe
Yoshihisa Matsumoto
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisor
Satoshi Kubo
Animation Supervision Assistance
Katsuya Yamamoto
Yoshiyuki Noujou
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
（入江）めまいや頭痛は？
Do you have a headache, or feel dizziness?
鼓膜は破れてはいないようですが…
The eardrum doesn't seem to have been ruptured.
（詩音）全然へっちゃらです
I feel just fine.
It really surprised me.
驚きましたよ
あなたが死ぬ気だったとは
You were actually prepared to die...
圭ちゃんに聞いたんですか!?
うわ…　めっちゃ恥ずかしいですね
Did you hear from Kei-chan!?
That's really embarrassing!
If I end up being the only one of us to survive by letting you take my place...
圭ちゃんに この場を譲って
私だけ生き残ったら―
お姉に一生 恨まれます
...Sis is going to hate me for the rest of her life.
私の思い人は もういないけど
お姉には いるもん
The person I love is already gone...
...but Sis still has hers.
The person you love...
あなたの思い人というのは
悟史(さとし)君のことですね？
...is Satoshi-kun, right?
（詩音）今頃どこにいるのやら
Who knows where he is right now...
生きているのか死んでいるのかも
分かりませんけど
I don't even know if he's alive or dead.
生きています
（魅音）え？
He's alive.
悟史君―
Satoshi-kun...
...is alive...!?
生き… てるの？
（葛西）今度は敵も警戒しています
奇襲は通用しません
The enemy is on their guard this time.
A surprise attack won't work.
赤坂さん　機関銃の経験は？
Akasaka-san, do you have experience with machine guns?
No.
ありません　拳銃だけです
Just handguns.
Then...
（詩音）
なら 私が行くしかないですね
...I guess I'll just have to go.
詩音　お前 耳 大丈夫なのかよ？
Shion.
Is your ear all right?
いくら何でも危険だよ
It's way too dangerous!
う…
（詩音）お姉 みんな 聞いて
Sis, and everyone else.
Listen.
I just found a reason to go to the clinic, no matter what it takes.
私 どうしても―
診療所に行かなければならない
用事ができたの
But I can't talk about it now.
でも今は話せない
If I do...
今 話すと
沙都子も来ると言いだすから
...Satoko is going to want to come with me.
Shion...
詩音…
Shii...
詩ぃ　きっと これは―
I'm sure this is a chance god created for you.
詩ぃのために
神様がくれたチャンスなのです
あなたは信じなかったことを悔い
信じ続けました
You repented for not believing, and continued to believe.
So please make the most of today.
だから 訪れた今日を大切に
Before your strong will, any trials ahead of you are no longer even trials anymore.
あなたの強い意志の前に―
目の前の苦難は
もはや苦難ではないのです
ウフ…　ありがとう
うん　うまくいきそうな気がします
Thanks.
I have a feeling everything will work out fine.
うまくいきますですよ
オヤシロさまの お墨付きなのです
It will.
You have Oyashiro-sama's blessing.
（詩音）ウフフッ
もう　何が何ですの？
What was that all about...
（梨花）にぱ～　にぱ～
さあ 始まりましたのです
And we're off!
オヤシロさま放送局 第23回
The 23rd Oyashiro-sama radio broadcast!
（羽入）この番組は自然の美しい
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)を紹介する番組なのです
This programme will acquaint listeners with Hinamizawa in all of its natural beauty.
（梨花）
それでは 初めにリスナーからの
おハガキを紹介なのです
Let's start by reading out some of the postcards sent in by our listeners.
（羽入）京都府のＤさんからの
おハガキです
This postcard is from B-san from Kyoto.
"Make a proper preview for once."
“もっと ちゃんとした予告を
してください”
You trying to pick a fight?
（梨花）ケンカ売ってんの？
（羽入）あうあうあう～！
Next time, the Festival Accompanying Chapter, Part Ten.
次回　祭囃し編 其の拾
「血戦」
"Bloody Battle."
（梨花）
ゆめゆめ 夜道に気をつけることね
Better watch your back when you go out at night.
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Ten
Bloody Battle